# Robert Isaac

209-417-7830

robert.isaac223@gmail.com

212 E Tuolumne Road, Turlock, CA 95382

## **SUMMARY**

Hands-on, motivated Software Engineer with verifiable success leading teams in delivering appropriate technology solutions for desktop and mobile products.

Comprehensive knowledge of platform development, enterprise architecture, agile methodologies, cloud services, and web-based applications.

Knowledge of full software engineering lifecycle including best practices of SE teamwork and SE processes such as Agile/SCUM and User Centered Design for providing good user experience.

Experienced linguist with more than three years of related experience in translating and interpreting from and to foreign languages as military linguist.

Possess a current Secret Clearance with the initial date of 2013.

## **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

Foreign language:

Farsi: General Professional Proficiency

Dari: General Professional Proficiency

#### Technical skills:

Problem solving
Critical thinking
Software development

C

C++ (proficient)

Python

Java (proficient)

JavaScript (proficient)

HTML (proficient)
CSS (proficient)
Bootstrap (expert)
GitHub (expert)

NodeJS

Trello (expert)
SQL (proficient)

**DBMS** 

### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer-front-end team leader, January 2020 – June 2020

San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA

Salary: School Project

Job Type: 60-80 hours per week

Supervisor: Dr. Dragutin Petkovic, (415) 338-2261

**Duties and Responsibilities:** 

- Design and deliver a software product that is maintainable, cost efficient, and satisfy the customers' specifications as part of a software development team.
- Coordinate with team leader and front-end team members in order to deliver the product on time and make the required adjustments requested by customer or the team leader.
- Manage and assign required task to the team and resolve issues raised during the product design and delivery.
- Confirm and execute the full lifecycle of the software development from planning to the point of delivery.
- Be flexible to any upcoming changes to the design or timeframe and make the necessary corrections to the given tasks.
- Take the full responsibility for the team outcomes and any possible flaw during the design and coding the product.

### Command Language Manager, October 2015 – February 2017

US Army, Fort Irwin, CA

Salary: \$40,000 Annually

Job Type: Full-time, Active duty

Supervisor: CPT Dahl, 51st TICO, RSS, Fort Irwin, CA

**Duties and Responsibilities:** 

- Manage and organize over 100 military linguists in their foreign language proficiency that includes testing, training, and recertifying the proficiency of multiple languages for each linguist.
- Report the status of the training and readiness of the assigned linguists to the commander and relevant agencies.
- Coordinate with multiple agencies to provide the necessary trainings to improve the proficiency of the assigned linguists.
- Recertifying the assigned linguists' language proficiency in both English and foreign language.

- Prepare and distribute the proper documents for linguists in order to get pay according to army regulations.
- Create and maintain a language tracker for the company for organizing and reporting the status
  of the readiness.

#### *Translator/Interpreter*, October 2013- September 2015

**US Army,** Fort Irwin, CA

Salary: \$40,000 Annually

Job Type: Full-time, Active duty

Supervisor: CPT Dahl, 51st TICO, RSS, Fort Irwin, CA

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Perform the fully role of the military escort interpreter and provide an accurate rendition of a sight translation from in English into another language and vice versa.
- Provide accurate bidirectional consecutive interpretation that conserving not only the message but also the tone, register, and intent.
- Transmit low register and colloquial speech into a more educated or military register and obtain a cultural understanding as to the specified language.
- Provide guidance to subordinate soldiers and supervises the maintenance and development of English and foreign language skills.
- Prepare written translation from a foreign language to English and vice versa.
- Provides and conducts language familiarization and cultural awareness trainings.

#### Palletizer, Product line worker, November 2010- September 2013

Foster Poultry Farms, Turlock, CA

Salary: \$8.15 per hour

**Job Type:** Full-time, 40 – 60 hours per week

Supervisor: Manuel Ortiz, (209) 668-5906

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Work as a product line worker, and remove and place the product on the conveyors.
- Responsible for packaging, labeling, and stacking the product and prepare them for shipping.
- Be flexible to work in different shifts and extra hours over the weekends.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, January 2021

San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, GPA 3.46

Bachelor of Science Minor in Persian Studies, January 2021

San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, GPA 3.46

Associate of Science in Mathematics, September 2018

College of San Mateo, San Mateo, CA, GPA 3.35

## **CERTIFICATION AND AWARDS**

**Certificate of Specialization: C++ Programming** 

September 2018, College of San Mateo, San Mateo, CA

**Certificate of Achievement: Command Language Manager** 

March 2016, Defense Language Institute, Joint Base McChord, WA

**Certificate of Achievement: Primary Leadership Development Course** 

August 2015, New Mexico Military Academy, Roswell, NM

**Certificate of Achievement: Combat Life Savor** 

August 2014, National Training Center, Fort Irwin, CA

Military Awards:

**Army Achievement Medal (2)** 

**Army Good Conduct Medal** 

**National Defense Service Medal** 

**Global War on Terrorism Service Medal** 

**Commissioned Officer Professional Development Ribbon** 

**Army Service Ribbon** 

### **TRAININGS**

Composite Risk Management, December 2017, 2 days, National Training Center, Fort Irwin, CA

Structured Self-Development (SSD-II), February 2016: 2 weeks (72 hours), Fort Bliss, TX

Command Language Program Manager, February 2016,

**Equal Opportunity Policy Training, December 2015,** 

Suicide Awareness and Prevention Military, December 2015,

Fundamental of Personnel Recovery CRS, December 2015,

Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention, December 2015,

Combat Trafficking in Persons, December 2015,

Intelligence Oversight Awareness Training, October 2015,

Level I Antiterrorism Awareness, October 2015,

Warrior (Basic) Leader Course, August 2015, 4 weeks (171 hours), New Mexico Military Academy, NM

SERE 100 and Command Code of Conduct CRS, January 2015,

Structured Self-Development (SSD-I), May 2014, 2 weeks (69 hours), Fort Bliss, TX

Introduction to Ammunition, May 2014, 3 days, National Training Center, Fort Irwin, CA

Operation Security (OPSEC) Awareness Training, May 2014,

Hazmat Familiarization and Safety in Transportation, May 2014, 1 days, National Training Center, Fort Irwin, CA

Interpreter/Translator Course, March - April 2014, 7 weeks, (385 hours), Intelligence School, Fort Huachuca, AZ

## **MILITARY SERVICE**

## 25 N, Nodal Network System Operator-Maintainer

Army Reserve, July 2017 - October 2018, B.T. Collins, Sacramento, CA

## 09L, Translator/Interpreter

Active Duty, October 2013 – February 2017, National Training Center, Fort Irwin, CA

**Highest Rank:** Sergeant/E5

Clearance: Secret (June 2013)

Veteran Preference: 10 point/ %30 Compensable